(+91) 7021292055 Mumbai, Maharashtra, IN kohinoorbharti7@gmail.com

# **Kohinoor Bharti**

# Full Stack Developer

GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

#### **OBJECTIVE**

I am Kohinoor, a **Full Stack Web Developer** with **2+ years** of combined professional and freelance experience. I specialize in creating interactive and web functional products using various technologies such as **ReactJS**, **Node.js**, **Django** and **Flask**. My approach to **Software Development** integrates technical expertise with a focus on delivering exceptional user experiences and scalable solutions.

#### **SKILLS**

**Backend Development** Python, Django, Flask, Node.js

Frontend Development HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Tailwind, Bootstrap, ReactJS, Redux

**Database** MySQL, MongoDB

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Full Stack Developer

July 2022 — Present

Dinosys Infotech Pvt Ltd

Mumbai

- Developed a CDR analyzer tool using Django, handling both front-end and back-end components.
- Led MySQL database setup for seamless data integration, optimizing storage and retrieval.
   Ensured data integrity and organization in the CDP tool through active participation in cleaning and str
- Ensured data integrity and organization in the CDR tool through active participation in cleaning and structuring.
- Contributed to a **Flask**-based social profiling app, implementing efficient user information retrieval automation.
- Played a role in hosting a Node.js server for a Flutter app.
- Configured an **Ejabberd** server for a chat application.
- Developed a bank statement analyzer to offer insights into user transaction behavior using Flask and ReactJS.
- Implemented a robust **Restful Web Services API** using **Node.js**, and **MongoDB** to facilitate seamless interaction between the mobile app and web app, incorporating modular design and run-time optimization techniques.
- Designed and implemented an end-to-end solution for efficient storage and retrieval of college data, leveraging multiple
  alias-matching algorithms to handle hundreds of thousands of records.

## **Desktop Support Engineer Intern**

Oct 2021 — May 2022

Mumbai

Buzzworks Business Services Pvt Ltd

- Managed physical **Ubuntu** servers for software testing, ensuring reliable environments for rigorous evaluations.
- Delivered prompt desktop support, resolving hardware and software issues to maintain seamless workflow.
- Conducted system upgrades and installations to optimize performance and compatibility for diverse environments.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **Twitter Sentiment Analysis**

Nov 2022 — Jan 2023

- Developed a learning platform CodeHelp using Next.js and Tailwind CSS, and managed content with Strapi CMS.
- Deployed the platform on AWS EC2 and CloudFront, ensuring fast and reliable delivery to over 100k monthly visitors.
- Created CodeHelp QuickCompiler, an online compiler for C, C++, Java, and Python programs.
- Designed Fruitbox Flex, an interactive game to teach CSS flexbox in a fun and engaging manner.

Dar Al Marefa Aug 2022

- Developed a content-driven website for a Dubai-based school with **dynamic pages**, **responsive design**, and **Next.js** for server-side rendering and optimization.
- Utilized Tailwind CSS for styling and used Strapi as a headless CMS for easy content management by non-technical users.
- Deployed the website using **Vercel** for fast and reliable delivery worldwide, leveraging its global CDN network.
- · Successfully implemented SEO best practices, resulting in Google search indexing and improved visibility.

## **EDUCATION**

# Ajeenkya DY Patil University

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology/Data Science — 8.4 CGPA

August 2017 — May 2021 Pune, Maharashtra

Divine Child Junior College, Mumbai

HSC — 60%

July 2015 — April 2017 Mumbai, Maharashtra

SGSK English School, Mumbai

April 2015

SSC-67%

Mumbai, Maharashtra

#### **CERTIFICATES AND PAPERS PUBLISHED**

**Dell EMC** Data Science and Big Data Analytics Certificate

Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Certificate

Motorcycle Security Sys- View paper

tem

Data Analysis Using SQL View paper